Guide to the James H. Laue papers, 1936-1999
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 5: Academic Papers, 1947-1990
  - Subseries 5.1: Student Papers, 1947-1966
    This subseries covers Laue's academic career from childhood in River Falls, Wisconsin through college and graduate school at Harvard. The subseries contains sociology papers Laue wrote as a student, college notebooks, course materials, church sermons, and correspondence with professors.
    - The American Family, late 1950s (Box 69, Folder 1)
      paper by Laue for Sociology 50
    - Answer Sheet / the Dove Counter Balance General Intelligence Test, January 1966 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Articles, Reviews (Correspondence on Same, etc.), 1963-1969 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - A Changing American Character?, 1960 (Box 69, Folder 4)
      by Seymour Martin Lipset
    - Child Development Testing, Fall 1958 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Childhood School Papers, 1947-1953 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Christianity and Communism, 1962 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - College Notebook - Constitutional History I, 1958 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - College Notebook - Constitutional History II, 1959 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - College Notebook - Contemporary Social Problems, Fall 1957 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - College Notebook - Economic Principles II, undated (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - College Notebook - General Psychology, Spring 1957 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - College Notebook - Individual Differences, Fall 1957 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - College Notebook - Introduction to Sociology 50, undated (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - College Notebook - Rural-Urban Communities, Fall 1957 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - College Notebook - Social Anthropology 75, undated (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - College Notebook - Social Psychology, Spring 1958 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - College Notes and Papers, 1957-1959 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - College Notes - Criminology, 1958 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - College Notes - Psychology of Learning, 1957 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - College Notes - Techniques of Social Science, 1958 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - The Cultural Context of Theology in America - Draft and Notes, 1964-1965 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Danforth Graduate Fellows and Danforth Teaching Fellows, 1959 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Data-Guide's [Philosophy / Psychology], 1959 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Dissertation Proposal - Religion and Southern Politics, by Donald M. Freeman, January 1962 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Geschwendler on Davies, ca. 1961 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Harvard Commencement, 1962, 1966 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Harvard Degree and Dissertation, Official Correspondence, Abstracts, 1961-1966 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Harvard Laboratory of Community Psychiatry - Article to Work Into Shape, 1964-1965 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Harvard Notebook - History 165a: History of the South, Fall 1961 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Harvard Notebook - Psychology 207: Advanced Analysis of Behavior, Fall 1961 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Harvard Notebook - Psychology 225: Personal Growth and Social Systems, Fall 1959 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Harvard Notebook - Social Relations 111: Sociology of Religion, Fall 1960 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Harvard Notebook - Social Relations 112: Primitive Religions, Fall 1961 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Harvard Notebook - Social Relations 136, Spring 1961 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Harvard Notebook - Social Relations 206: Pro-Seminar for Sociology, part 1 of 2, Fall 1960 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Harvard Notebook - Social Relations 206: Pro-Seminar for Sociology, part 2 of 2, Spring 1961 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Harvard Notebook - Social Relations 215: Social Anthropology, Fall 1959 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Harvard Notebook - Social Relations 216: Problems and Concepts in Sociology, Spring 1960 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Harvard Notebook - Social Relations 217: Problems and Concepts of Clinical Psychology, Fall 1959 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Harvard Notebook - Social Relations 218: Problems and Concepts of Clinical Psychology, Fall 1959 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Harvard Notebook - Social Relations 232: Sociology of Religion of Max Weber, Fall 1961 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Harvard Notes - Sociology of the South, 1961-1962 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Harvard Papers, 1960 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Harvard Papers, 1961-1964 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Harvard Papers - Durkheim, Social Relations 206, Fall 1960 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Harvard Papers - "Paths to Insight" and "Participant Observation Study of Personality and Social Systems", 1960 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Harvard Papers - "The Sit-Ins: A New Decade and a New Generation?" and "Give as Much as You Receive: An Analysis of the Work of Emile Durkheim and Marcel Mauss", May 1960 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      Social Relations 284
    - Harvard Tutorial, K-House, 1960-1961 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Social Relations 98
    - Harvard University Memorial Church Sermons, 1959-1960 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - History and Theory of Sociology, 1958-1964 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Job Offers - Grinnell College and Kansas, 1964-1966 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Mormons, ca. 1950, 1962 (Box 73, Folder 8)
      articles and news clippings
    - Purposive Community Change in Consensus and Dissensus Situations, Winter 1966 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Reinhold Niebuhr, 1961 (Box 73, Folder 10)
      notes and magazine article
    - Religion and Race - Northview SS Class, 1962-1963 (Box 73, Folder 11)
      sermons, notes, news clippings, and brochures
    - Religion and Schools - Carleton College, 1960-1961 (Box 73, Folder 12)
      news clippings and sermons by David J. Maitland and James H. Laird
    - Religion - Non Academic, 1960-1961 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      St. Anthony Park Congregation Church newsletters and news clippings
    - Religious Attitudes Survey, ca. 1960 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - "Religious Perspectives of College Teaching", 1952 (Box 74, Folder 3)
      by Talcott Parsons
    - Riesman 136 - Hot Accessories, 1956-1961 (Box 74, Folder 4)
      from class with David Riesman
    - Riesman 136 - Mailings, Not Hot, 1960-1961 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Riesman 136 - Most Important Related Items, 1961 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Riesman 136 - Readings, 1961 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - The Rosicrucian Order, ca. 1962 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Rural/Urban - "Dekalb County: Politics in Suburbia," by Emily Hartshorne, May 19, 1961 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Rural/Urban Sociology - "A Community Identification Survey," by Gerald Johnson and Jim Laue, November 1957 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Sermons by Dr. David J. Maitland, Carleton College Chaplain, 1960-1961 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Sermons Delivered to the Northview Congregation of the Methodist Church, 1962-1963 (Box 74, Folder 12)
      Roanoke, Virginia
    - Skinner - Psychology 207, 1958-1964 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Skinner - Psychology Notes, 1961-1962 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Social Relations 215 - "The Role of Music in Formation of the Navaho Modal Personality", January 1960 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Social Relations 216, 1959-1962 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      bibliography and notes on personality and mental health
    - Social Stratification, 1958 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Sociology of Religion Abstracts, ca. 1963 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Special Examination in Sociology, May 1961 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Spinoza, 1958 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Tillich, 1959 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - WCCO Radio - Family Picnic, July 8, 1954 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - WCCO Radio - Monthly Program Schedule, 1954 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - WCCO Radio News Parade and Pierce County Heritage, Vol. 4, 1954, 1974 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - WCCO Radio - Saturday, July 10, 1954 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - "William Randolph Hearst - Lucky or a Genius?", June 1958 (Box 75, Folder 14)
      essay by James Laue
    - "World Revolution: The College Student and the YMCA", 1959 (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - Zen, 1960 (Box 75, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 5.2: Professional Papers, 1966-1999, bulk 1971-1993
    This subseries covers Laue's academic career as a researcher at the Harvard Medical School Laboratory of Community Psychiatry, as a professor of sociology and urban studies at Washington University-St. Louis and the University of Missouri-St. Louis in the 1970s and 80s, and as a professor of Conflict Resolution at George Mason University in the late 80s and early 90s. The subseries contains journal articles and commencement speeches written by Laue, course materials, academic exercises used in workshops on conflict mediation, and biographical materials prepared for annual reviews and tenure application.
    - "1960's Reflection" and "The 1960's: A Sociologist's View from Justice and the Movement", 1969 (Box 75, Folder 17)
      papers by James Laue
    - Academic Exercises - "Children and the Burb", ca. 1989 (Box 75, Folder 18)
    - Academic Exercises - Church Disputes (Box 75, Folder 19)
    - Academic Exercises - "Country Living Magazine Sweepstakes", 1989 (Box 75, Folder 20)
      CDR
    - Academic Exercises - "Dispute Resolution Design: Health Organization" and "Divorce Eggs" (Box 75, Folder 21)
    - Academic Exercises - "Facilitating a Community Workshop", 1989 (Box 75, Folder 22)
    - Academic Exercises - "Jewelbox Square Neighborhood Dispute", February 1987 (Box 75, Folder 23)
      Conflict Clinic, George Mason University
    - Academic Exercises - Joint Problem Solving, Positional Bargaining, and Negotiation (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Academic Exercises - "Land Rezoning Dispute," "Neighborhood Care, Inc.," and "Oak Acres", 1980s (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Academic Exercises - "Manassas Battlefield" and "Neighborhood Association and the Cement Company", 1989-1990s (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Academic Exercises - "Rainbow Park Land Dispute", 1971 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Academic Exercises - "South Atlantic Crisis" and "U.S.-USSR Negotiations" (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Academic Exercises - "Spaghetti O's", 1985 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Academic Exercises - "Sunrise Services", 1990 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Academic Exercises - "Ugli Orange Case" (Box 76, Folder 8)
      R. J. House
    - Academic Freedom and Tenure (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - "Advocacy and Sociology", 1978 (Box 76, Folder 10)
      by James Laue, reprinted from Social Scientists as Advocates: Views from the Applied Disciplines
    - American Sociological Association, 1973 (Box 76, Folder 11)
      correspondence and papers
    - Andrew R. Laue, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 12)
      resume with notes on back
    - "Application of Social Science Knowledge to the Community Organization Field", 1967 (Box 76, Folder 13)
      by Roland L. Warren
    - Biographical Data, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Book Review of George Henderson's Human Relations: From Theory to Practice, Spring 1975 (Box 76, Folder 15)
      by James Laue, published in the Journal of Intergroup Relations
    - Book Review of Raymond L. Hall's Black Separatism in the United States, undated (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Book Reviews, 1975-1976 (Box 76, Folder 17)
      Laue's reviews of On Race and Marginal Men and Women, by Charles Willie, and At the Heart of the Whirlwind, by John P. Adams
    - Central College, November 6-8, 1989 (Box 76, Folder 18)
      correspondence and workshop materials
    - Chapter 12: "Serving Human Needs: Some Lessons and Guidelines", 1989 (Box 76, Folder 19)
      draft chapter by James Laue for The Conflict Resolution Handbook
    - Chesapeake Bay, 1988 (Box 76, Folder 20)
      letter and article re: commission to clean up the Chesapeake
    - Clinical Sociology Newsletter, Summer 1986 (Box 76, Folder 21)
      brief article by Laue titled Getting to the Table
    - Code of Ethics Preamble, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 22)
      draft with corrections
    - Community Crisis Intervention Study, Department of Psychiatry at Harvard Medical School, 1969-1971 (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - CONF 501: Introduction to Conflict Resolution, Spring 1989 (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - CONF 602: Third Party Roles, Resources and Ethics, Fall 1990 (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - CONF 617: Philosophy and Methods of Conflict Research II, Spring 1991 (Box 76, Folder 26)
    - CONF 623: Community/Organizational Conflict Resolution Lab and Simulation, part 1 of 2, Spring 1991-1992 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - CONF 623: Community/Organizational Conflict Resolution Lab and Simulation, part 2 of 2, Spring 1991-1992 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - CONF 633: Laboratory and Simulation in Conflict Processes III, Fall 1987 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - CONF 635: Structural Sources of Conflict, Fall 1989 and Fall 1990 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - CONF 636: Third Party Roles, Resource, and Ethics, Fall 1992 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - CONF 642: Proseminar on Conflict (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - CONF 701: Doctoral Pro-Seminar, Fall 1988 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - CONF 740: Mediating Public Policy, Spring 1991 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Conflict Resolution Book Contributions, 1978 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Consortium on Peace Research Education and Development (COPRED) and GMU Center for Conflict Resolution, 1987-1988 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Curriculum Vita [and biography], 1967 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Curriculum Vita, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Curriculum Vita, 1975-1976 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Curriculum Vita [update materials], 1978-1980 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Curriculum Vita, 1984-1986 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Curriculum Vita [update materials], 1986-1987 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Curriculum Vita, 1987-1992 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - "Desegregation in the St. Louis Public Schools: Brown and Beyond", 1979 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      article by Richard H. Patton and James Laue, 58 pages
    - Emory Course Materials, Articles, and News Clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - "Ethical Considerations in Choosing Intervenor Roles", Summer 1982 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Ethical Society Speech, February 1986 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - "The Ethics of Social Intervention" - Draft with Comments, ca. 1988 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - The Ethics of Social Intervention, part 1 of 2, 1973-1984 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - The Ethics of Social Intervention, part 2 of 2, 1973-1984 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - "Faculty Power", September 1968 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      by McGeorge Bundy, published in the Atlantic Monthly
    - Falcon Features: University of Wisconsin-River Falls, Summer 1978 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      Alumni Association newsletter
    - Financing Community Economic Development, 1985 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      MIT and the Institute for Management and Community Development
    - Garrow/Carlson Publishing Contract for Direct Action and Desegregation, 1960-1962, 1989 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - George Mason University (GMU) Center for Conflict Analysis and Resolution (CCAR) and Center for Study of Conflict, University of Ulster, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      includes program for joint meeting on June 10-13 and papers on conflict resolution in South Africa and Northern Ireland
    - GMU CCAR and Conflict Clinic, Inc., 1989-1992 (Box 79, Folder 7)
      includes correspondence, memoranda, course evaluations, and a letter to Diane Rehm on Waco, Texas
    - GMU CCAR and Conflict Clinic, Inc., 1987-1992 (Box 79, Folder 8)
      notes and correspondence
    - GMU CCAR Brochures, ca. 1988-1990 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - GMU CCAR Course Syllabuses and Comprehensive Exam Questions, 1991-1992 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - GMU CCAR Discussion Outline and Mission Statement, 1988-1991 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - GMU CCAR Fifth Annual Lynch Lecture, 1991-1992 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - GMU CCAR General Information, 1987 (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - GMU CCAR Introduction, 1988 (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - GMU CCAR Introduction [duplicate], 1988 (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - GMU CCAR Newsletters, 1990-1995 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - GMU CCAR Working Papers and Reports, part 1 of 2, ca. 1990-1993 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - GMU CCAR Working Papers and Reports, part 2 of 2, ca. 1990-1993 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - GMU Faculty Bibliography, 1989 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - GMU International Week 1991 - "The World at a Crossroads" (Box 80, Folder 5)
      program
    - GMU - Lynch Professor of Conflict Resolution Inauguration, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 6)
      includes a promotional flyer, invitation, press release, letter from Edwin Lynch to James Laue, and bio sketch, The Story of My Life as told by Vernon M. Lynch 1968
    - GMU - Proposal for Program in Conflict Management, 1980 (Box 80, Folder 7)
      proposal submitted to the Council of Higher Education for Virginia
    - "Getting to the Table: Creating the Forum for Negotiations in Deep-Rooted Conflicts", 1992 (Box 80, Folder 8)
      by James Laue, 17 pages
    - Handbook of Applied Sociology - "Conflict Intervention", 1981 (Box 80, Folder 9)
      chapter by James Laue
    - Harvard Medical School Laboratory of Community Psychiatry, 1970 (Box 80, Folder 10)
      bio, brochure, memorandum, and mission statement
    - Harvard University Preliminary and Interim Report, 1968, 1971 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - "A History of Third Party Intervention in Community Conflict", 1973 (Box 80, Folder 12)
      essay by James Laue, 23 pages
    - "The Idea that Can Unite the World...", March 1988 (Box 80, Folder 13)
      by Libby Rouse
    - "Implementing Desegregation Plans" and "Intervening in School Desegregation", 1977-1980 (Box 80, Folder 14)
      by James Laue and Daniel J. Monti
    - "Intervening in School Desegregation Conflicts: The Role of the Monitor", 1980 (Box 81, Folder 1)
      by James Laue and Daniel J. Monti, 66 pages
    - "Intervenor in Community and Racial Disputes: A New Way of 'Being a Sociologist'?", 1975 (Box 81, Folder 2)
      by James Laue, 20 pages
    - An Introduction to Negotiation and Conflict Resolution, 1993 (Box 81, Folder 3)
      GMU Institute for Conflict Analysis and Resolution, 102 pages
    - Iowa Wesleyan College Commencement Program, 1989 (Box 81, Folder 4)
      lists a sermon by Laue, "In the Heart of the Heartland---Where Peace Grows"
    - Issue Management Forum for the Porch Band of Creek Indians, July 15-17, 1988 (Box 81, Folder 5)
      GMU Center for Interactive Management
    - "Jefferson Hazardous Waste Negotiation," A Two Hour Negotiation Exercise, April 22, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      prepared by Vicki Arroyo and Lawrence Susskind
    - Job Marketability Info, 1959-1981 (Box 81, Folder 7)
      mostly correspondence
    - Journal Articles and Essays by Laue, 1961-1986 (Box 81, Folder 8)
      printed on 8.5x11" paper
    - Journal Articles and Essays by Laue, 1968-1988 (Box 81, Folder 9)
      printed in pamphlet form
    - Journal Articles and Essays by Laue, 1974-1988 (Box 82, Folder 1)
      includes drafts and notes
    - Journal Articles and Notes, 1985-1988 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Journal of Intergroup Relations, featuring Special Issue Editor, James Laue, November 1975, Summers 1982 and 1983 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Juniata College, 1988-1991 (Box 82, Folder 4)
      includes mission statement, press releases, news articles, and correspondence
    - Lentz International Peace Research Award, 1973-1974 (Box 82, Folder 5)
      notes and correspondence re: dedication of Lentz Award to Washington University-St. Louis
    - Letters and Comments Regarding Publications, 1968-1992 (Box 82, Folder 6)
      Jay Press, Inc., Jossey-Bass, Inc., Hemisphere Publications
    - "Liberation or Revolution? A Theory of Political Polarization", ca. 1981 (Box 82, Folder 7)
      by William C. Meulemans
    - McDonnell Project, Spring 1972 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Mediating Urban Policy, 1982 (Box 82, Folder 9)
      American Sociological Association proposed chapter outline
    - Mediation: A Citizen's Solution - Report on Conference Held on January 26, 1980 (Box 82, Folder 10)
      Council for Community Services, Inc.
    - Negotiation and Mediation in the Conflict Resolution Process: A Workshop Led by James Laue, October 28, 1989 (Box 82, Folder 11)
      Johns Hopkins University
    - Notes, ca. 1988 (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - Notes, February 5, 1993 (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Peace and Conflict Studies Journal, Vol. 6, No. 1, 1999 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      In Memory of James Laue
    - Peace College Curriculum, mid 1950s (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Peace Movement Dynamics: Sociological Views, ca. 1990 (Box 83, Folder 3)
      a prospectus by John Lofland and Sam Marullo
    - "Peace Stories" - University of Missouri-St. Louis Commencement Speech, 1986 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - "A Peacemaker's Journey: Personal Perspectives on the Emergence of Dispute Resolution", June 26-27, 1987 (Box 83, Folder 5)
      agenda and list of participants in the Consultation on Dispute Resolution in Higher Education
    - Peacemaking and Conflict Resolution at Bethel College, September 22, 1977 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Preliminary Proposal - University of Missouri South African Exchange Program, 1987 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Program on the Analysis and Resolution of Conflict (PARC), 1987 (Box 83, Folder 8)
      newsletter and workshop materials
    - Proposal to Develop Curriculum Modules, 1987 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Publishing Agreement and Correspondence Regarding The Practice of Peacemaking: Concepts, Skills and Ethics of Conflict Management, 1983 (Box 83, Folder 10)
      book edited by James Laue, Margaret S. Herrman and Edward S. Weeks
    - Racial Mediators, 1974-1975 (Box 83, Folder 11)
      draft chapter outline, memorandum for publishers, prospectus, and publisher correspondence
    - "Reparation and Reciprocity...", April 1989 (Box 83, Folder 12)
      Wit Business School report by Loet Douwes Dekker; contains Laue Citation
    - "Resolution: Transforming Conflict and Violence", November 17, 1987 (Box 83, Folder 13)
      inaugural lecture by James Laue, ICAR Occasional Paper 7
    - Responses to the Powell Memorandum, 1973 (Box 83, Folder 14)
      by James Laue and William Danforth
    - "Sanctions, Resources, and a Typology of Powerholders", 1965 (Box 83, Folder 15)
      essay by Ronald L. Nuttall, Erwin K. Scheuch and Chad Gordon
    - "Science and the Scientific Attitude", undated (Box 83, Folder 16)
      by T. E. Lasswell, 20 pages
    - Social Science 136: Character and Social Structure in America - Supplement, 1969-1970 (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - Social Science 136 - Letters to Students, 1969-1971 (Box 83, Folder 18)
      Harvard Medical School Laboratory of Community Psychiatry
    - The Sociological Quarterly, Vol. 28, No. 3, 1987 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Sociology 106: Social Problems and Social Issues, Spring 1975 (Box 84, Folder 2)
      Washington University-St. Louis
    - Sociology 221: Interracial and Intercultural Relations, Spring 1973 - Fall 1974 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Sociology 300: Workshop on Racial and Cultural Minorities, Summer 1971 (Box 84, Folder 4)
      Wisconsin State University-River Falls
    - Sociology 344: Problems of Urban Community, Winter-Fall 1978 (Box 84, Folder 5)
      University of Missouri-St. Louis
    - Sociology 426: Community and Regional Conflict Intervention, Summer 1986 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 434: Sociological Reporting, Fall 1978 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 466: Social Policy and Community Planning, 1977-1982 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Sociology 470A: Seminar in Sociological Issues: Conflict Resolution and Social Policy, 1976 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Sociology 471: Social Problems and Social Policy, Fall 1974 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Sociology 595 (Section 92): Conflict Intervention and Social Change", Spring 1975 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Sociology Classes, 1974-1975 (Box 85, Folder 1)
      course outlines, tests, reading lists; Washington University-St. Louis
    - "Sociology for...", April 1977 (Box 85, Folder 2)
      by James Laue, draft paper for symposium on "Advocacy in the Disciplines"
    - Survey of Courses Dealing with Topics Relevant to Peace Studies and Conflict Resolution, ca. 1985 (Box 85, Folder 3)